恶魔城
第四季 第４集
‎住在这里的人走得很匆忙
Whoever left here left in a hurry.
‎来点光吧
A little light?
‎说到走得匆忙
Speaking of leaving in a hurry,
‎你真的想躲开扎姆菲尔
you really wanted to get away from Zamfir.
‎坐下
Sit down.
‎床很舒服
Comfy bed.
‎这就是你想我们独处的原因吗
Is this why you wanted us to be alone?
‎我想躲开所有人至少那么一小会
I wanted to get away from everyone else for five fucking minutes.
‎我们几周来疲于应对
All we've been doing for weeks is reacting,
‎一件事接着另一件事
being bounced from one thing to the next.
我们有时间思考和讨论 ‎才会做到最好
And we do best when we've got time to think and talk things over.
‎我很高兴你这么想
I'm glad you think so.
‎我又不是很傻
I'm not completely stupid.
‎我很高兴你这么想
I'm glad you think so.
‎哈哈 真好笑
Ha ha. Very funny.
‎听着 我们不再被动应对 ‎开始主动出击
Listen, we need to stop reacting and start acting.
‎就算被杀 我宁愿选择出击
If I'm gonna get killed, I'd rather choose it
‎也不愿意落入别人的圈套
than get tricked into it by someone else.
‎好吧
All right.
你想从哪里说起
Where would you like to start?
‎从头说起
At the beginning,
‎我们还没有陷入困境的时候
before we find ourselves backed into the end.
‎是你们给我送的信吗
You sent me a letter?
‎是的
Yes.
‎欢迎来到德内什蒂
Welcome to Danesti.
‎我想这里从前有过好日子
I presume it's seen better days.
‎更平静的日子
Quieter ones.
‎我是村长格丽塔
I'm Greta, the village headwoman.
‎叫我阿鲁卡多吧
Call me Alucard.
‎不用特指
No "The."
‎马里乌斯…
Did Marius...
你说的是你的骑手吗
Was that your rider?
‎很遗憾
I'm afraid not.
‎他在路上遇袭受伤 失血过多而亡
He was attacked en route and bled out from his wounds.
‎他的马驮着他走完剩下的路 ‎手里还拿着你的信
His horse carried him the rest of the way with your message in his hand.
‎哦
Oh.
‎我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
‎我们不仅失去了他
Well, he's not the only one we've lost.
‎但他是他家最后一个人 ‎所以才冒险上路
But he was the last of his family, which is why he risked the journey.
‎但我还是希望…
Still, I'd hoped...
‎我想这就是希望得到的结果
That's what hoping gets you, I suppose.
‎我还要救很多人 阿鲁卡多
I have a lot more people to save, Alucard.
‎趁着还能休息 大家休息一下吧
Get some rest, everybody, while you can.
‎你们遭到攻击多久了
How long have you been under attack?
‎四天了
Four days.
‎开始只有一个畜生
First it was just one of those bastards.
每晚越来越多
More every night.
‎我们昨晚勉强撑下来
We barely made it through last night.
‎很幸运 只死了三分之一的人
We're lucky only a third of us are dead.
‎你愿意帮我们吗
Will you help us?
‎我肯定能帮你做些什么
I'm sure I can do something for you.
‎我对用魔法打仗不感兴趣
I'm not interested in magic tricks and one fight.
‎照顾这些人是我的责任
These people are under my care.
‎无论花多长时间 ‎你愿意留下来保护他们吗
Will you stay and defend them for as long as it takes?
‎-我说过…  ‎-请你理解
- I said... - You have to understand.
‎我不了解你
I don't know you.
‎你在三十多公里外住了几个月
You've been 20-odd miles away for months.
‎你在森林里跑来跑去
You creep around the forest.
‎你把尸体挂在奇怪城堡外面的木桩上
You've got bodies on stakes outside your weird castle.
‎你明显是半吸血鬼 你身上有酒味
You're obviously half-vampire, and you stink of wine,
‎在我看来 你差不多是个疯子
and you appear to me to be at least half-crazy.
‎但我能想到的救兵只有你
But you were the only possible advantage I could think of.
‎我不想对低调的霸气表示钦佩
I don't need to be impressed by low-key swagger.
‎我想让你答应救这些人
I need you to commit to saving these people.
‎因为我要是救不了他们 ‎我的生命也不值得留恋
Because my life isn't worth living if I can't save theirs.
‎说完了吗
All done?
‎可以吗
Did it work?
‎是的
Yes.
‎那我说完了
Then I'm all done.
‎谢谢
Thank you.
‎刚才的出场真的很精彩
And that was one hell of an entrance.
‎没错 确实如此
Yes, indeed so.
‎你真是个非常英勇的年轻人
You really are a very impressive young man.
‎我不擅长令人作呕的暴力 请你理解
Sickening violence isn't especially in my skill set, you understand,
‎但我能认出行家 无论是哪个领域
but I can recognize a fellow expert, no matter what the field.
‎天啊 这家伙
Oh, God. This one.
‎你是阿德里安·特佩斯吗
You would be Adrian Tepes, yes?
‎是的
Yes.
‎请允许我介绍一下自己
Do allow me to present myself.
‎我是圣日耳曼伯爵
I am the Count Saint Germain,
‎常驻欧洲各大宫廷的学者
scholar in residence to many of the great courts of Europe.
‎你为什么躲在瓦拉吉亚的厕所里
Why are you cowering in a latrine hut in Wallachia?
‎这是厕所吗
Oh.  Is this a latrine?
‎我还以为有人给吓坏了
I just... I just thought someone had gotten very scared.
‎我在旅行 先生
I'm traveling, sir.
‎瓦拉吉亚的动荡时代
Interesting times in Wallachia.
‎我觉得一位学者应该亲眼见证
I felt that a man of letters should bear witness.
‎目前为止你的旅行开心吗
And are you enjoying your tourism so far?
‎这段旅程...
it has been, um...
‎给人很多启发
enlightening.
‎圣日耳曼 陛下
Saint Germain, Your Majesty,
‎欧洲各大宫廷的神秘学家 书记员和法律顾问
occultist, scribe, and counsel to the great courts of Europe.
‎圣日耳曼 皇帝陛下
Saint Germain, Your Imperial Majesty,
‎占星家 情报员和学者
astrologist, intelligencer, and... and scholar.
‎圣日耳曼 殿下
Saint Germain, Your Royal Highness,
‎占卜师 预言家和黑魔法巫师
soothsayer, prophet, and practitioner of the dark arts.
‎圣日耳曼 阁下
Saint Germain, Your Grace,
‎图书馆员 书记员和学者
librarian, scribe, and scholar.
‎圣日耳曼
Saint Germain,
‎您卑微的仆人...
your humble servant in, um...
‎听候您的差遣
whatever you may need.
‎别对这样的人动手动脚 ‎你这粗鲁的小混蛋
Do not grope for a person like that, you rude little clump of frog shit.
‎圣日耳曼
Uh, Saint Germain.
‎利索的武力不是我的强项 ‎不过 我肯定认得出行家 深表钦佩
Swift violence is not my forte, but I certainly recognize and admire an expert.
‎你游历过这么多地方 令人难以置信
The sheer breadth of your travels is incredible.
‎你回到这个破地方 ‎老实说 让我感到惊讶
I'm frankly amazed you ever bothered coming back to this shit hole,
‎也很高兴
and delighted.
‎我需要钱 但我也想在图书馆里寻宝
I needed the money, but I also wanted to pick through the library here.
‎我知道世上有一本书
I understood there was a volume
‎讲述一个叫无限回廊的地方
regarding a place called the Infinite Corridor,
‎但我找不到这本该死的书
but I can't find the damned thing.
‎就是这个
This is it.
‎就是这本书
This is the book.
‎没错 让我们踏上一生难忘的旅程
And, yes, offering us the journey of a lifetime.
‎如果你真的想这么做...
If you really want to do this...
‎那我们就去做
then that is what we will do.
‎为你做什么都行
Anything for you.
‎抓住我的手
Take my hand!
‎求你了
Please!
‎无限回廊是通往许多其它世界的通道
The Infinite Corridor is a route to many other worlds.
‎事实上 这是个传送门系统
It is in fact a system of doors to other lands,
‎通往跟我们时间和空间不同的世界
separated from our own by space and time.
‎很久以前 ‎我在无限回廊中...
A long time ago, I lost someone very dear to me...
‎失去了挚爱之人
in the Infinite Corridor.
‎从那以后 ‎我一直在寻找再次进入的方法
And I have been looking for a way back in ever since.
‎通往回廊的入口很少 间隔很远
Portals to the Corridor are few and far between,
‎而且忽隐忽现
and they drift in and out of existence.
‎我要关闭回廊了
I'm closing the Corridor!
‎快出去
Get out now!
‎谢谢
Thank you!
‎谢谢你们两位
Thank you both!
‎后会有期
I'll see you again!
‎不
No! No! No!
‎究竟在哪里
Where is it?!
‎我知道就在这里
I know it's here!
‎我只是… ‎我控制不了
I just... I have no control!
‎为什么我控制不了
Why can't I control this?!
‎我回来了
I made it back!
‎喊一声 我就能找到你
Shout so I can find you!
‎是我
It's me!
‎你好啊
Hello, you.
‎你的朋友最近去了‎回廊里的另一个地方
Your friend has recently moved on to another sphere within the Corridor.
‎很遗憾
I am sorry.
‎她去哪里了
But wh-where did she go?
‎这还真不好说
I cannot be certain.
‎我没有去找她...
I have not looked for her...
‎圣日耳曼
Saint Germain.
‎你知道我吗
You know me?
‎我知道很多事
I know much.
‎我是炼金师
I'm an alchemist.
‎我也是炼金师
So am I.
‎不
No.
‎你不算
Not really.
‎你很久以前就半途而废了
You fell by the wayside long ago.
‎我一直...
Well, I've been...
很忙 ‎但我仍然相信炼金术的目标
busy, but I still believe in the goals of the path.
‎相信
Believe in?
‎却不尽力吗
Not committed to?
‎生活往往让人无法尽心尽力 对吗
Well, life tends to mitigate against complete commitment, doesn't it?
‎她在哪里
Wh-where is she?
‎所以你发现自己来到这里
And so you find yourself here.
‎没有力量 不能控制...
With no power, no control...
‎也没有前进的路
and no way forward.
‎根本不可能控制回廊
It's impossible to control the Corridor.
‎她在哪里
Where is she?
‎不 才不是呢
No, it's not.
‎你知道不是这样
You know it's not.
‎你见过回廊被控制
You've witnessed it being controlled.
‎没错 是怪物控制的 他杀了几十个人 ‎用他们的灵魂做燃料
Yeah, by a monster who had dozens of people killed to use their souls as fuel.
‎所以别说控制不了回廊
So don't say it's impossible to control.
‎我不是杀人狂
I am not a mass murderer.
‎她在哪里 听到没
Where is she, damn it?
‎圣日耳曼...
Saint Germain...
‎炼金术的真正目的是什么
what is the true goal of alchemy?
‎你记得吗
Do you remember?
‎还是说 你已经完全放弃了这条路
Or have you left the path entirely?
‎这项壮举是伟大的工作 ‎协调世界的混乱
The magnum opus, the great work, reconciling the chaos of the world.
‎这项伟大工作的成果是什么
And what is the result of the great work?
‎同体者 经过腐败和净化
The Rebus, the putrefied and purified fusion
‎精神与物质融入男女同体的身体
of matter and spirit in a body both male and female.
‎这是测试吗
Is this a test?
‎两个身体融为一体 圣日耳曼
Two bodies into one, Saint Germain.
‎两个灵魂
Two souls.
‎你在开玩笑吧
You're not serious.
‎我看起来像开玩笑吗
Do I not look serious?
‎你是说炼金过程的最终成果
You're claiming that the final victory of the alchemical process
‎是用同体者来控制无限回廊
is using a Rebus to control the Infinite Corridor.
‎没错
Here I am.
‎那让我看看你的同体者
Show me your damned Rebus, then.
‎不用管我的同体者
My Rebus cannot be looked upon.
‎这是秩序和混乱的产物
It is a creature of order and chaos,
‎包含自然的人性和超自然的恐怖
of natural humanity and supernatural horror,
‎经过火焰的净化 在地狱里腐烂
purified by fire and sent to rot in Hell.
‎你听懂我在说什么吗
Do you understand what I'm saying?
‎我希望没听懂
I hope not.
‎你懂的
You understand.
‎你懂你的炼金术必须召唤什么东西吗
You understand what your alchemy must summon, don't you?
‎你说的是必须召唤"谁"吧
You mean "who," don't you?
‎我必须召唤 结合 融为一体的人
Who I must summon, bind, and fuse into one?
‎只有这样你才能有力量穿越回廊
Only then will you be able to travel the Corridor with power.
‎我要给你看这个
I will show you this.
‎这掌管着许多人的死亡
This is charged with many deaths.
‎它会在你选择的任何地方打开回廊
It will open the Corridor wherever you choose.
‎如果我拿走这个 ‎你就会被困在回廊里
If I take this, then I leave you stranded in the Corridor.
‎我完全控制了穿越回廊
I travel the Corridor with complete control.
‎我像女神一样 ‎每年穿过100个不同的宇宙
I dance through a hundred different universes every year like a goddess.
‎我为什么要离开
Why would I ever want to leave?
‎谢谢
Thank you.
‎不用谢
You are welcome.
‎这对你没用 ‎除非你尽力投入炼金术的工作
This is useless to you unless you commit to the work of alchemy
‎完成你该做的事
and do what needs to be done.
‎你不能帮我找到她吗
Couldn't you just help me find her?
‎我已经尽力帮你了
I've helped you as much as I can.
‎剩下的是你的使命 ‎不是我的
What remains is your task, not mine.
‎要尽力
Commit.
‎我会的
I will.
‎我尽力了 我来了这里 不是吗
I am committed. I'm here, aren't I?
‎你要做出牺牲
You must sacrifice.
‎我牺牲了
I have.
‎不
No!
你只是失去了某些东西
You have lost something.
‎那不一样
That is not the same.
‎但感觉是一样的
Bloody feels like it.
‎你要做出牺牲 ‎自愿放弃
You must sacrifice, give willingly.
‎放弃什么 留下什么
Give what? What's left?
‎放弃一切
Everything.
‎牺牲你的伦理道德
Sacrifice your ethics, your morals.
‎牺牲你的灵魂去完成使命
Sacrifice your soul to the task.
‎你要为之放弃一切 ‎你做出牺牲的时候必须非常痛苦
You must give everything to it, and you must cause pain in the doing of it.
‎你真的爱她到牺牲一切的地步吗...
Do you love her enough to do that...
‎圣日耳曼
Saint Germain?
‎我什么都愿意做...
I'll do anything...
‎做什么都行 只要能亲口告诉她...
anything to be able to actually tell her...
‎我爱她
that I love her.
‎六周前
‎把它交给我
Just give it to me!
‎天啊
Oh, God!
噢 我的天
Oh, God.
‎为什么你不…
Wh-wh-why didn't you just...
‎为什么你不直接帮我
wh-why couldn't you just help me?!
‎天啊 对不起
Oh, God, I'm sorry.
‎对不起
I'm so sorry.
‎我不是故意的 我…
I didn't mean to. I...
‎你为什么不帮我
Why couldn't you help me?!
‎为什么没人帮我
Why won't anyone just fucking help me?!
‎现在看看你
And now look at you.
‎现在...
Uh, now...
看着我
look at me.
‎‎这的确是我在这些地方听过跟牲畜胡搞
That was indeed the most suave tale about sexual congress with livestock
最斯文的故事了
that I've ever heard in these parts,
‎但趁着你还没把破罐子凑到臭嘴边
but before you lift your stinking jar to your stinking jaws,
‎‎你现在要告诉我 德古拉城堡的最终位置在哪里
you will now tell me, what was the final location of Dracula's castle?
‎你就是那个著名的圣日耳曼吗
Would you be the famous Saint Germain?
‎我很高兴
I have that pleasure.
‎那么你是…
And you would be...
‎伦敦的瓦尼 先生
Varney of London, sir.
‎朋友的朋友告诉我 ‎我们有共同的计划
Friends of friends tell me we have a project in common.
‎那是什么计划 伦敦维克的瓦尼
And what might that be, Varney of Lundenwic,
‎千年吸血鬼 乞丐和流浪汉
thousand-year-old vampire beggar and tramp?
‎你听说过我
You've heard of me.
‎世世代代的智者写过
Generations of the learned
‎大老远都能闻出你身上的臭味
have written of detecting you from a thousand paces by your stench.
‎我再说一遍...
I say again...
‎什么计划
what project?
‎让德古拉伯爵重返人间
Returning Dracula to this world.
‎一切就是这样
And that's everything.
‎严格执行计划是关键
Strict adherence to the plan is crucial.
‎不过 如果...听我说 圣日耳曼…
But what if... and hear me out, Saint Germain...
‎如果我在这里杀了你
what if I just killed you here,
‎吸光你的血 ‎完成你的计划 又会怎样
drank all your blood, and did your plan myself?
‎德拉甘 可怕的德拉甘
Oh, Dragan, feared Dragan,
‎传说中百战百胜 杀人一千的德拉甘...
storied Dragan of a hundred ambushes and a thousand dead...
‎没错 你绝对可以在这里杀了我
yeah, you could absolutely kill me right here,
‎但你不能实施我的计划
but you cannot enact my plan,
‎因为你没有手段 也没这个智慧
because you don't have the skills or the wit.
‎闭嘴
Shut up.
你说话像牛放屁
You sound like a cow farting.
‎你到底想不想 ‎让你亲爱的德古拉伯爵起死回生
Do you want your precious Dracula back or not?
‎是的
Yes.
‎那你就他妈的老实点
Then get back in your fucking pram.
‎没有我 你做不成这件事
You can't do this without me.
‎按我的命令行事
Obey my instructions.
‎我会杀了你
I will kill you.
‎你要照我说的做
Do as you're fucking told!
‎把他们都派到德内什蒂
Drive them all towards Danesti.
‎剩下的交给我
I'll do the rest.
‎你可以日后再杀我
You can kill me afterwards.
‎没错 记住该怎么做 老伙计
Ah, yes. Remember the drill, old boy.
‎"迷人的地方 疲惫的旅人
"Charming place. Weary traveler.
‎身上有很多钱 只想找个地方睡觉"
Many coins. Just a simple place to sleep."
‎这种日子很快就要到头了
It'll all be over soon enough.
‎真是太可惜了
What a damned shame.
‎所有这些小生命
All these little lives.
‎直起身子 老兄
Straighten up, man.
‎他们都有生命
They all have lives.
‎你什么都没有
You have nothing.
‎那样公平吗
Is that fair?
‎你能听到吗
Can you hear that?
‎我什么都没听到
I hear nothing.
‎我也没听到
Me, neither.
‎有人来了
Something's coming.
‎有人把你那匹蠢马带回来了
Someone brought your stupid bloody horse back.
‎那是一匹好马
That's a good horse.
‎她很厉害 对吗
She's very good, isn't she?
‎真可惜
It's a shame.
‎可惜什么
What is?
‎普通人有这样的天赋
Well, such a talent with the common people,
‎却浪费在这里 你不觉得可惜吗
but it's wasted out here, don't you think?
我想她待在她应该待的地方
I think she's probably right where she's supposed to be.
‎他们来自16公里外的村庄拉萨
They're from Lasa, a village about ten miles away.
‎走了好几个小时才到
They've been walking for hours.
‎他们也被袭击了吗
They were attacked, too?
‎他们的村子被烧毁了
Their village was put to the torch.
他们说 不只是他们
They said they're not the only ones.
‎‎这群人包括这个地区其他五个村庄的难民
This group includes refugees from five other villages in the region.
‎原来如此
I see.
‎他们逃出来了
They escaped.
‎他们活下来了
They survived.
‎他们有很多人死于吸血鬼和黑暗生物的袭击
They lost many people to vampire and night creature feeding attacks.
‎有意思 ‎他们为什么要烧掉村庄
Interesting. Why would they be burning the villages, though?
‎如果是吸血鬼指使的话
If vampires are involved,
‎这不是我们看惯了的‎黑暗生物的盲目破坏
this isn't the blind destruction we're all used to with night creatures.
‎他们要吸血 才能支撑自己继续战斗
They're conducting feeding to sustain them through continued battle.
‎他们要清除房舍 ‎阻止别人提供援助和见证
They're removing shelter and the possibility of aid and witnesses.
‎这件事复杂得令人不安
This is troubling in its complexity.
‎当然 我不是军人
I am of course not a military man,
‎不过我曾经为将军和国王出谋划策
although I have certainly advised generals and kings,
‎但我能否问一句 ‎这个村子没有天然屏障吗
but might I suggest that this village is inherently indefensible?
‎目前还没什么用 对吗
It hasn't worked out well, so far, has it?
‎你也许说得有道理 圣日耳曼
You may have a point, Saint Germain.
‎也许在我们弄清楚怎么回事前
Perhaps, just until we all find out what's going on,
‎你也许可以负责把剩下的人
perhaps the remaining persons in your charge
‎转移到更安全的地方 ‎比如...
might be moved to a more secure location, like, um...
你的城堡...
y-your castle...
‎可以考虑下
Possibly.
‎老天爷又看我不顺眼了
And God shits in my dinner once again.
‎不
Oh, no.
‎我真的要变成贝尔蒙特了
I really am turning into Belmont.
‎现在的生活有意义吗
Is life even worth living now?